HO HOANG LONG

BUSINESS ANALYST

Date of birth: Oct 25, 2000

Gender: Male

Phone: 0368 021 579

Email: longhh2510@gmail.com

Address: Thu Duc City, Ho Chi Minh City

OBJECTIVE

As a person who is sensitive, eager to learn, and wants to find simple optimal solutions for software to meet business needs. I have more than 1 year of implementing Loyalty projects for corporations in the position of Business Analyst at FPT Software. Therefore, I possess skills in business analysis, business requirements of enterprises from which to offer suitable software products, and meeting the needs of business customers, especially enhancing the user experience.

To further enhance my knowledge and skills, I would like to work in an innovative, challenging, and rewarding environment and a place that provides an extensive knowledge base to enhance my talents.

EDUCATION

2018 - 2022 Banking University of Ho Chi Minh City

Major: Management Information Systems

GPA: 3.21/4.00

Jul 2021 - Oct 2021 True Skill Center

Advanced Skill For Business Analyst and Product Owner

EXPERIENCE

Feb 2022 - Present FPT Software

IT Business Analyst

Domain: Loyalty System

PROJECT: Loyalty For E-commerce Domain

Feb 2023 - Present

Business Analyst (PIC)

Summary: Developing mobile applications integrating loyalty systems and e-commerce systems.

Main responsibilities:

- Analyze the response of the Loyalty system when integrated.
- Participating in the process of designing UI interfaces between Loyalty and E-commerce.
- Write integrated FRS documents for E-commerce partners.
- Analyze and design the partner's API to respond to the application.
- Support 2 BA team members to write design analysis documents.

PROJECT: Loyalty For Fintech Domain

June 2022 - Present

Business Analyst (Assistant Lead)

Summary: Developing a Loyalty system and mobile application that allows to accumulation of points based on transactions from banking applications, using bonus points on Mobile SDK for focal things such as gift exchange, and partner points exchange.

Main responsibilities:

- Participate in the process of writing and completing BRD according to the bank's professional requirements.
- Work with related departments to collect requirements and consider feasibility.
- Participating in the requirements analysis process, giving the User cases needed in the Backlog to deploy to the project.
- Analyze customer experience to design UX for the Loyalty SDK app and design Mockup for the Loyalty app using Figma.
- Participate in UI review and UI management.
- Participate in the process of coming up with highly feasible high-level solutions.
- Write documents to develop functions according to the needs of partners.
- Write API integration documentation for Loyalty and Fintech system linking functions.
- Analysis of API specification documents from 3rd party partners.
- Write system integration documents (partners integrate gifts, integrate exchange points).
- Manage and support 3 members of the BA team in the process of participating in the project, implementing the work on schedule from the Leader.
- Onsite at the partner's agency directly supports the UAT phase of the project.
- Write user manuals and system operating documents.
- Support customers in the production phase of the project, and provide solutions to issues when customers have problems using the application.

Achievement:

- The project has gone live.

PROJECT: Loyalty For Real Estate Domain

April 2022 - July 2022

Business Analyst Member

Summary: Developing a Loyalty application that integrates gift supply partners and features.

Main responsibilities:

- Write documentation to guide partners to design APIs for gift system integration.
- Participate in the analysis and development of system integration documents from 2 gift suppliers.
- Write Smart OTP security authentication documents.
- Write API integration design documents for partner applications.

PROJECT: Loyalty For Technology Corporation

Feb 2022 - June 2022

Business Analyst Member

Summary: Developing a Loyalty mobile application for the corporation.

Main responsibilities:

- Design UX and mockup for Loyalty app using Figma, Participate in UI implementation.
- Write design documents and API integration between Loyalty and Mobile systems.
- Write system design documents required by BALead.

Achievement:

- The project has gone live.

SKILLS

Core Skills:	Stakeholder analysis and Mapping, Requirements Engineering, Requirement Elicitation, Requirement analysis, Requirement Modelling, Requirement Validation, Requirement management, Business Impact Analysis, Business Process Improvement, SWOT Analysis, Design Thinking, Full Project Life cycle, SDLC, User stories, Mockup,
Soft Skills:	Communication, Stakeholder management, Scope management, Decision making, Analytical thinking, Critical thinking, Proactiveness, Problem-solving, Google search,
Documentation	Business Requirement, System Requirement Specification, Functional Requirement Specification, Use Case Documentation, Integrative Systems Analysis, User Manual.
Technical Skills:	SQL, API.
Tools	Draw.io, Figma, Postman, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft PowerPoint, Microsoft Word, Microsoft Outlook, SharePoint, Jira, Confluence.

REFERENCES

Le Dang Don Phat Quy Nguyen

Business Analyst Team Leader at FPT Software Product Owner at CIMB Vietnam Email:

Email: phatndd@utop.io nguyenlethanhquy@gmail.com Mobile:

Mobile: 0917 299 969 0374 567 558